<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Danno Projects</title><link>https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Danno Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Printer Monitor: Because Printers Are Out to Get Us</title><link>https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/printer_monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/printer_monitor/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="printer-monitor-because-printers-are-out-to-get-us">Printer Monitor: Because Printers Are Out to Get Us&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>No one wants to be the printer whisperer—especially for low-cost, unmanaged printers. After one too many toner emergencies (always at 4:59 PM on a Friday), I decided to automate the pain away. If you’re tired of being the “toner psychic,” this Python script is for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Printers are needy, dramatic, and love to run out of toner at the worst possible moment. This project checks their status, logs the drama, and even emails you when it’s time to order more supplies. No more “surprise, you’re out of magenta!” moments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing Excel with a SharePoint List for Inventory Management</title><link>https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/inventory_mgmt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.dannoprojects.com/posts/devops/python/inventory_mgmt/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Managing a small inventory in Excel can be convenient at first—but as the inventory grows, &lt;strong>Excel&lt;/strong> often becomes more of a bottleneck than a solution. I recently decided to shift from an Excel-based approach to a &lt;strong>SharePoint List&lt;/strong> for better flexibility, multi-user access, and integration potential with APIs (like Dell’s warranty service).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, I’ll walk you through:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Why I moved from Excel to SharePoint&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>How I set up the SharePoint List&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Automating warranty checks with the Dell API&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lessons learned and future ideas&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-why-move-away-from-excel">1. Why Move Away from Excel?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Excel is great for quick data entry, but it shows its limitations when:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>